Guide to the Williamson Family papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Williamson Family Papers,
1776-1961
Williamson family.
4 linear ft. (8 boxes, 1 flat folder, & 3 Flat Boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1355
7467767
History
The archive deals principally with three families related by marriage: Abeel, Williamson and Codwise. All of the families had strong connections to New York City through business and property holdings
Scope and Content
Correspondence, documents, manuscripts, photographs, and printed materials of the Williamson, Abeel, and Codwise families of New Brunswick NJ and Saint Croix in the West Indies.
The Abeel family materials include correspondence from Gen. Nathanael Greene (about the American Revolutionary Army), from David Abeel (concerning his missionary activities in China), and from others. There are documents concerning Abeel family real estate in New York City and other matters, family photographs, and related materials.
The Codwise family material includes correspondence concerning their affairs in early New York City and in Saint Croix, where they had inherited a sugar plantation (Mount Victory) from the Rogers family. These letters discuss business interests, slave revolts, and life in Saint Croix. There are also many family photographs.
There are correspondence and legal and business papers of Nicholas Williamson (1845-1902) and his family in New Brunswick NJ and his company, the Novelty Rubber Company, in New York City. There are many contracts and patent agreements with Charles and Henry B. Goodyear for rubber manufacturing and business correspondence and related papers from 1851 until 1887. Nicholas Williamson was Mayor of New Brunswick from 1895 until 1900 and there are papers relating to municipal affairs as well as his family's real estate holdings.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 5 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Uncataloged Correspondence
Series III: Manuscripts and Documents
Series IV: Photographs
Series V: Printed Material
Subjects
Novelty Rubber Co.; Abbott, Austin, 1831-1896.; Abeel, David, 1804-1846.; Abeel, James, 1733-1825.; Abeel family.; Demarest, David D., 1819-1898.; Devan, Thomas T., d. 1890.; Goodyear, Charles, 1800-1860.; Greene, Nathanael, 1742-1786.; Harriman, Edward Henry, 1848-1909.; How, Samuel Blanchard, 1790-1868.; Howell, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1844-1933.; Kellogg, Stephen W. (Stephen Wright), 1822-1904.; Ludlow, H. G. (Henry Gilbert), 1797-1867.; Rice, John Warren, d. 1931.; Schuyler, John, 1829-1895.; Storer, Agnes Williamson, b. 1870.; Throop, Enos Thompson, 1784-1874.; Van Rensselaer, James Fleming, 1844-1900.; Warner, Charles F. (Charles Forbes), b. 1851.; Williamson, Douwe Ditmars.; Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902.; Williamson family.; Wirt, William, 1772-1834.; New Jersey.; Mount Victory (Saint Croix, V.I.: Plantation).; Saint Croix (V.I.).; New Jersey--Genealogy.; Mayors--New Jersey--New Brunswick.; Municipal government--New Jersey--New Brunswick.; Real property--New York (State).
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
[source] Gift, 2001 accn number
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Abbott, Austin, 1831-1896 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, New York, 20 April 1855, (1p a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
    [(re. the patent papers of Charles Goodyear)]
  - Abeel, David, 1763-1840 To Gerard Rutgers, New Brunswick [NJ], 12 Feb 1819, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [(re. James Abeel)]
  - _____ To Mrs Gerard Rutgers, Lake George [NY], 16 March 1819, ( 2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - _____ To MS Rutgers, New Brunswick NJ; 14 January 1832, ( 1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Abeel, David, 1804-1846 To Samuel Blanchard How, 1790-1868, Macao, 30 October 1839(?), (3p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - _____ To Mr & Mrs Nicholas Williamson, Macao, 6 March 1840, (4p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - Codwise, David, 1780-1864 To Agnes Maria Codwise Burlock (Mrs David), 1798-1886, New York, 6 January 1823[i.e., 1824], ( 2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [(re. the death of her husband)]
  - Codwise, David, 1780-1864 To Nicholas Williamson, 1811-1862, White Lake NY, 20 July 1855, (3p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - _____ To George Washington Codwise, Vernon NJ, 14 Aug 1857, ( 4p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Codwise, George, 1732-1814 To David Codwise, 1780-1864, New York, 14 July 1802, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Codwise, James, 1772-1861 To George Washington Codwise, Saint Croix, 22 October 1843 & [1852], (a.l.s. 2) (Box 1)
  - Constable, Susan Maria LivingsTon (Mrs John) To Martha Livingston Codwise (Mrs David), Boston, 17 December 1841, (4 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Demarest, David D, 1819-1898 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, New Brunswick NJ, 22 June 1869, (1p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - Devan, Thomas T, d1890 To NicholasWilliamson, 1845-1902, New Brunswick NJ, 7 September 1874, (3p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Greene, Nathanael, 1742-1786 To James Abeel, 1733-1825, Smiths Clove [NJ], 11 June 1779, (1p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - Harriman, Edward Henry, 1848-1909 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, New York, 25 March 1878, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Howell, Benjamin Franklin, 1844-1933 To Clara Augusta Gurley Williamson (Mrs Nicholas), 1849-1918, N.p., 15 August 1902, ( 2p. ms.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kellogg, Stephen Wright, 1822-1904 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, Waterbury [CT], 12 March 1862, (1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ludlow, Henry Gilbert, d1867 To [Agnes Maria Codwise Burlock (Mrs David), [1798-1886], Perth Amboy [NJ], 2 July 1824, (4p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - Rice, John Warren, d1931 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, New Brunswick NJ, 26 February 1879, (6p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Schuyler, John, 1829-1895 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, [New York], 24 Feb 1877, ( 2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Throop, Enos Thompson, 1784-1874 To Martha Livingston Codwise (Mrs David), Naples & Paris, 10 Dec 1841 & 20 March 1842, ( 2 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Van Rensselaer, James Fleming, 1844-1900 To Nicholas Williamson, 1845-1902, New Brunswick NJ, 16 March 1879, (6p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1762-1856 To Douwe Ditmars Williamson, 1789-1869, Flaggtown [i.e., Perth Amboy] NJ, 12 November 1849, (1p. a.l.s.,) (Box 1)
  - _____ To Nicholas Ditmars Williamson, 1789-1869, Flaggtown NJ, 29 April 1850, ( 1p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 To, N.p. [1853], (1p. a.l.,) (Box 1)
    [(draft re. the rubber patents of Charles Goodyear)]
  - _____ To [Charles Goodyear, 1800-1860], N.p., [1853], ( 1p. a.l.) (Box 1)
    [(Draft re. Goodyear's rubber patents)]
  - Wirt, William, 1772-1834 To Martha LivingsTon Codwise (Mrs David), Washington, 10 February 1831, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [(re. the death of his wife)]
- Series II: Uncataloged Correspondence
  - B (Box 1)
  - Blood, Mariana Williamson (Mrs William H) (Box 1)
  - Blood, Mattie Williamson (Box 1)
  - Blood, William Henry (Box 1)
  - Bryant, Elizabeth Rebecca Codwise (Box 1)
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise (Mrs David), 1798-1886 (Box 1)
  - C (Box 1)
  - Codwise, Cornelia Frederica De Coninck, 1806- (Box 1)
  - Codwise, David O & Mary (Box 1)
  - Codwise, George Washington & Beatrice (Box 1)
  - Codwise, John Rogers, 1817-1857 (Box 1)
  - Codwise, Rebecca Rogers (Mrs James), 1782-1850 (Box 1)
  - Cook, Hetty Gurley (Mrs Paul) (Box 1)
  - Delano, Laura A (Box 1)
  - G (Box 1)
  - H (Box 1)
  - Janeway, Frank L (Box 1)
  - Kenney, Charles (Box 1)
  - M (Box 1)
  - R (Box 1)
  - Reilly, Augusta STo rer Williamson (Box 1)
  - S (Box 1)
  - Storer, Agnes Williamson, 1870-1961 (Box 1)
  - Thompson, Alexander R (Box 1)
  - Trotter, Jonathan (Box 1)
  - Voorhees (Box 1)
  - W (Box 1)
  - Williamson (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Augusta M (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Catherine Bulkeley (Mrs Douwe D), 1854-1917 (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Charles Gurley, 1894-1947 (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, Jr (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1851-1918 (Box 1)
  - Williamson, James Abeel (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Mary AB (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Mary Ann Abeel (Mrs Nicholas), 1790-1864 (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 (Box 1)
  - Williamson, Sarah Cook (Mrs Nicholas) (Box 1)
  - Misc (Box 1)
- Series III: Manuscripts and Documents
  - Account for a farm, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Abeel, David, 1763-1840 Prize ships, etc.: notes from Kent's Commentaries, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Abeel, David, 1804-1846 Biographical essay, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Abeel, James, 1733-1825 Drawing found in his Bible, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Blood family Diagram of bedroom, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise (Mrs David), 1798-1886 Receipt for 2 puncheons of rum for $69.46, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Genealogical notes, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Storer, Agnes Williamson, 1870-1961 "New Brunswick, New Jersey, in colonial days", [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Agnes Bookmarks for Nicholas and Clara Williamson, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1789-1869 (Comptroller of New York City) List of municipal funds at New York banks, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Mr & Mrs Douwe Ditmars, Jr Notebook and sketchbook, [n.d.], (1 volume) (Box 2)
  - Williamson Memorial Chairs [in the Second Reformed Church of New Brunswick N.J.] (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Edwin B Wedding invitation, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Mary Rebecca Burlock (Mrs Nicholas), 1819-1857 Cook book of recipes and remedies, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Two memorandum book covers with notes (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 Receipt for $250, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Medical lecture, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Medical notes (Box 2)
  - Poem (Box 2)
  - Prescription (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Ruth A Her characteristics, [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Abeel, James, 1733-1825 His appointment as Major in the New York Regiment, 11 August 1776 (Box 2)
    [(copy)]
  - His recommendation of Christopher Codwise for a captain's commission, 27 October 1776 (Box 2)
  - Abeel, David, 1763-1840 Copy (1877) of his notes about his voyage on the Alliance in 1781, with a clipping (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1789-1869 His indenture of apprenticeship To John Nielson for 6 years to learn bookkeeping & commerce, (1 page a.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by James Neilson, John Neilson, John Van Dike, & Nicholas Williamson)]
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise (Mrs David), 1798-1886 Decorative calligraphic exercise, 10 October 1814 (Box 2)
  - Burlock, David, 1780-1823 Copy of his will, including an account of his assets (Box 2)
  - Abeel, David, 1804-1846 Abeel The Lord's Prayer written in Chinese by David Abeel (Box 2)
  - Notes in his hand, found in his Bible (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Mary Rebecca Burlock (Mrs Nicholas), 1819-1857 Silhouettes cut while she was at school in Litchfield (Box 2)
  - Codwise, Caroline Matilda Financial trust for her sisters & niece, 31 December 1832 (Box 2)
    [(2 copies)]
  - DeWitt, Anna Deed of sale of a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ to William W. Perrine for $4,200, 31, July 1832 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Anna DeWitt and by John Terhune as witness and notary)]
  - Perrine, William W and Sarah Perrine Deed of sale of a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ to Alexander McClelland for $5,000, 30, Dec 1833 (Box 2)
    [(signed by William and Sarah Perrine, by Joseph Ford as witness and notary, and by N. Booraem as clerk)]
  - McClelland, Alexander and Mary Ann McClelland Deed of sale of a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ to John Acken for $5,500, 28, September 1835 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Alexander and Mary Ann McClelland, by James S.Nevins as witness and notary, and by N. Booraem as clerk)]
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1789-1869 Conveyance of the contract with George Rapelje for the Glass House Farm in New York City to Nicholas Williamson for $800, ms.d.s., 10 January 1835 (Box 2)
  - Smylie, Edward Assignment of lease of a house and lot on Madison Street in New York City to Nicholas Williamson for $4,000, 7 March 1836, (ms.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Nicholas Williamson and by Alfred A. Smith as witness and attorney; including 2 receipts for $1,750 signed by Smylie)]
  - Williamson, Mary Rebecca Burlock (Mrs Nicholas), 1819-1857 Diary of her stay in Great Barrington MA [at school?] (Box 2)
  - Abeel, David, 1804-1846 To David Abeel, 5 September 1838, (poem) (Box 2)
  - Maun, John M Incumbrances against the Conover family in, Somerset County NJ, 31 August 1840 (Box 2)
  - Abeel, David, 1804-1846 Quit claim deed for land in New Brunswick NJ to William Parsons executed by Douwe Ditmars Williamson and Nicholas Williamson as Abeel's attorneys, 22 November attorneys, by Daniel P. Ingraham as witness and notary, and by Nathaniel Jarvis as clerk (Box 2)
  - Abeel, Gertrude, Douwe Ditmars Williamson, and Mary Ann Abeel Williamson (Mrs Douwe D) Quit claim deed for land in New Brunswick NJ to William Parsons, 17 Nov 1841 (Box 2)
    [(Signed by G. Abeel, M.A. Williamson, D.D. Williamson, and by Joseph Ford, Daniel P. Ingraham, Nathaniel Jarvis, and N. Booraem)]
  - Abeel, Jane Hassert (Mrs David), 1766-1842 Deed of sale of land in New Brunswick NJ to William Parsons for $200, 17 November 1841 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Jane Abeel, Joseph Ford as witness and notary, and by N. Booraem as clerk)]
  - Smith, Gerrit Deed of sale of 40 acres of land in Franklin County NY to Major Johnson for $1, 1 Nov 1847, (p.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by James W. Nye as notary)]
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, Mary Ann Abeel Williamson, Gertrude Abeel, and Nicholas Williamson Deed of sale of land in New Brunswick NJ to Elbert Stults for $210, 31 July 1847, (p.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Richard Goodman as witness and notary and by N. Booraem as clerk)]
  - Castnir, James Release of mortgaged land in Franklin NJ to Nicholas Williamson for $1, 28 February 1848, (ms.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(in the hand of Thomas A. Hartwell and signed by him as witness and notary and by William Kennedy as clerk)]
  - Codwise, David, 1780-1864 Memorandum of D. Codwise's houses chargeable with Croton water rents (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Major Deed of sale of 40 acres of land in Franklin County NJ to Caroline Adams for $1, (ms.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Aaron Bradly and by Frederick Hughson)]
  - Bergen, Cornelius Description of a tract of land, March 29 1850 (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1789-1869 Statement of cash in hand, Sept. 30th 1850 (Box 2)
    [(signed by L.B. Whitmore, Teller)]
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 Deed for pew #65 for $80 in the First Reformed Dutch Church, Bound Brook NJ, 1 April (Box 2)
    [(signed by George J. Van Neste)]
  - Trotter, Jonathan T Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Offer to the Union India Rubber Co, 16 Oct. 1852 (Box 2)
  - Accounts, (2 p.) (Box 2)
  - Agreement to vacate the Naugatuck India Rubber Company factory, 25 May 1853 (Box 2)
  - Burr, Henry Promissory note for $861.15 to the National Rubber Co., 23 September 1853, (1 a.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(endorsed by Nicholas Williamson)]
  - Copy of contracts between Charles and Nelson Goodyear and Lucius B. Potter re. the Goodyear rubber patents, 30 January 1852 & 1 January 1853 (Box 2)
  - Spear, Calvin Flint, Sect Organizational papers of The National India Rubber Co, 10 Feb 1853 (Box 2)
  - Newell, Azariah D Deed of sale for land in New Brunswick NJ to Oliver B Gaston for $1,080, 1 April 1854 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by James H. Newell as witness and notary and N. Booraem as clerk)]
  - Calhoun, John C Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Receipt to Nicholas Williamson for $700, 1 July 1854, (a.d.s.) (Box 2)
  - Clark, JW, & Co Protesting the non-payment of Henry Burr's promissory note of 23 September 1853, 26 May 1854 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Henry Clark, notary)]
  - Goodyear, Charles, 1800-1860 Agreement with John C. Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson, 23 May 1854 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Calhoun, Williamson, George Basil Dixwell, and C.F. Winthrop)]
  - Goodyear, Charles, 1800-1860 Covenant agreement with John C. Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson, 1854 (Box 2)
    [(draft)]
  - Goodyear, Charles, 1800-1860 License and covenant agreement with John C. Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson, 23 May 1854 (Box 2)
  - Goodyear, Henry B Agreement with John C Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson, 24 May 1854 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Calhoun, Goodyear, Williamson, Austin G. Day, and John MacKenzie)]
  - Goodyear, Henry B License agreement with John C Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson, 1854 (Box 2)
  - Goodyear, Henry B Partnership with John C Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson to manufacture India rubber buttons, 24 May 1854 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Calhoun, Goodyear, and Williamson, with later amendments: 17 December 1854, 23 January 1855, 29 January 1855, and 2 February 1855)]
  - Porter, Lucius P Partnership with John C Calhoun and Nicholas Williamson to manufacture India rubber buttons, etc, 29 May 1854, (a.d.s.) (Box 2)
  - Porter, Lucius P Receipt to Nicholas Williamson for $625, 3 April 1854, (a.d.s.) (Box 2)
  - Porter, Lucius P Receipt to Nicholas Williamson for $625, 29 May 1854, (a.d.s.) (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 Receipt for $497.57, 18 Feb 1854 (Box 2)
  - Keeley, Denis Receipted bill for $15.88 to Mr Codwise, 28 May 1855, (a.d.s.) (Box 2)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Account Debts, 1 May 1855 (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, Jr Account of Nicholas Williamson, 1 December 1855 (Box 2)
  - Winkler, L Memorandum of canes, 13 November 1855 (Box 2)
  - Gaston, Oliver B Bond for $2,000 to John S Voorhees, 1 April 1856 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Warren Hardenbergh as witness and 14 receipts for payment are added, signed by Voorhees, 1856-1864)]
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Labels -- Drawing of boilers (Box 2)
  - Codwise, George Washington Will, 21 August 1857 (Box 2)
    [(witnessed by E.R. Codwise, Francis D. Fox, and Samuel M. Fox)]
  - Conover, Elias Release of property to Nicholas Williamson, 30 April 1857 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by George A. Vroom as witness and notary and by Samuel S. Hartwell as clerk)]
  - Conover, Peter V Release of property to Nicholas Williamson, 8 April 1857 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by George A. Vroom as witness and notary)]
  - Gaston, Oliver B & Sarah A Gaston Deed of sale of a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ to John D Wortman for $4,000 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Abraham V. Schenck as witness and notary and by George A. Vroom as clerk)]
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 Mortgage bond to John Clark for $7,700, 23 February 1858 (Box 2)
  - Wortman, John D Deed of sale for a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ to Sarah A Gaston for $4,500 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by George R. DutTon as witness, C.L. Hardenbergh as notary, and George A. Vroom as clerk)]
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts (Box 2)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts, 1857-1859 -- Bill, 28 March 1859 -- Receipt from Aetna Insurance Company to Nicholas Williamson for $11.50 -- Receipt from Aetna Insurance Company to Nicholas Williamson for $21.60 (Box 2)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts, 3 items -- Price list for India rubber buttons (Box 2)
  - Clark, John Receipt to Nicholas Williamson for $435, 10 October 1860 (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1789-1869 Invitation addressed to Mr & Mrs John A. Pool, 1 November 1860 (Box 2)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts, 4 items -- Bill of lading for 3 casks coal pitch from The North British Rubber Co., 2 August 1860 (signed by C.S. Colton, Captain) -- Order for samples from D.D. Williamson In Edinburgh -- Receipt from the Aetna Insurance Company to Nicholas Williamson for $11.50, 12 June 1860 -- Receipt from the Aetna Insurance Company to Nicholas Williamson for $21.60, 12 June 1860 -- Receipt from The Globe Express for 1 box shipped to D.D. Williamson in Edinburgh, 31 August 1860 (signed by L.W. Morris) (Box 2)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) List of shareholders (Box 2)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1802 Receipt for army equipment, 20 May 1862 (Box 2)
    [(also signed by John T. Hill and by David A.Storer)]
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts -- Receipt to S.W. Kellogg for expenses of $75 (Box 2)
  - Codwise, David, 1780-1864 Lease of a furnished house and lot at 27 St. Mark's Place in New York City to David C. Green for seven months at $500 (Box 2)
    [(signed by Codwise and Green and by Agnes M. Burlock as witness)]
  - Gaston, Sarah A & Oliver B Gaston Deed of sale of a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ for $5,000 to DeWitt T Reiley, 16 November 1864, (p.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Woodbridge Strange as witness and notary and by J. Elmer STo ut as clerk)]
  - Reiley, DeWitt T Bond for $3,000 to Isaac G Smock, 16 November 1864, (p.d.s.) (Box 2)
    [(also signed by Woodbridge Strange as witness and bearing 4 receipts, 1865-1868, signed by Smock and by Joseph Fisher)]
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 Account of his estate (Box 2)
  - Reilly, C Receipt for $50 for moving organ (Box 3)
  - Troy Female Seminary Graduation certificate of Clara A. Gurley [Williamson], 27 June 1866 (Box 3)
  - Smock, Isaac G Assignment of mortgage for $3,000 to Jacob Stout and others, 2 May 1867, (p.d.s.) (Box 3)
  - Stout, Eliza W Deed of sale for a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ for $6,500 to Mary F Van Rensselaer, 16 May 1867, (p.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(also signed by Edward S. Vail as witness and notary and by J. Elmer Stout as clerk)]
  - Stout, Eliza W Deed of sale for a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ for $6,500 to Mary F Van Rensselaer, 16 May 1867, (p.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(copy made by C.S. Hill, 30 April 1873)]
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Will, 28 August 1867, (a.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(witnessed by J.C. Metzger and by G. Kimmerle)]
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) List of shareholders (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Receipted bill for $15 from Wilson & Wallis for Mrs Williamson's will, 17 July 1868 (Box 3)
  - College of Physicians & Surgeons Receipt for $140 to Nicholas Williamson -- 7 tickets of admission (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, JT Receipt for $25 to Nicholas Williamson for tuition, 1 July 1869 (Box 3)
  - Rutgers College Diploma of Nicholas Williamson (Box 3)
    [(signed by many)]
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, Jr Receipt for $48 to Leonard Paulson, 30 Oct 1869 (Box 3)
  - Blood, Mariana Williamson (Mrs William H) Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Power-of-attorney to Nicholas Williamson, 4 January 1869, (ms.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(also signed by William H. Blood as witness)]
  - Williamson, Augusta M Power-of-attorney to Nicholas Williamson, January 1869, (p.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(also signed by Agnes M. Burlock as witness)]
  - Brown Brothers & Co. (New York) 2 bills of exchange for £100 to Mr Ellis, 9 December 1870 (Box 3)
    [(Nicholas Williamson paying D.D. Williamson's bills while in Europe)]
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons Nine tickets of admission (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Note of the exchange rate, £100 = $541.67 (Box 3)
  - Storer, Agnes B Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Power-of-attorney to Nicholas Williamson, 14 January 1870, (ms.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(also signed by David A. Storer)]
  - Dendrobium Nobile Watercolor drawing of flowers, 17 April 1871 (Box 3)
  - New York University Diploma for Nicholas Williamson's M.D. degree, March 1871 (Box MapCase 14/10/3)
    [(signed by many officials)]
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) List of shareholders, 21 January 1871 (Box 3)
  - Bryant, Elizabeth Rebecca Codwise Receipt for $600 in gold to Agnes M. Burlock, 20 May 1872, (a.d.s.) (Box 3)
  - Burke, Mary Receipt to Drs. Baldwin & Williamson for $10.75 (Box 3)
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons Commencement program, 28 February 1872 (Box 3)
  - Oversize diploma for Nicholas Williamson's M.D. degree, 22 February 1872 (Box 3)